http://www.biblesociety.org.uk/privacy-policy/

Our website uses cookies to improve your online experience. Accept | Find out more
Donate now Basket Login/Register Search
About usWhat we’re doingGet involvedExplore the BibleLatestShop
Main navigation
Donate About usWhat we’re doingGet involvedExplore the BibleLatestShop
Toggle navigation
Shopping basket
Profile area
Search
Bible Society Privacy Policy Bible Society Privacy PolicyWho are we?In this policy, ‘we’, ‘our’ or ‘us’ refers to Bible Society, a registered charity in England and Wales (232759). This also includes Christian Research, Open the Book and our trading company Bible Society Resources Limited (registered company number 5450490).Our address is: Stonehill Green, Westlea, Swindon, SN5 7DG.Your PrivacyWe respect your privacy and want to communicate with you in a way that suits you, in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Your privacy is important to us and this policy explains how we use your personal information and keep it secure.What is personal information?Personal information covers any data that enables us to identify you as an individual. This could include, name, address, telephone number, email address or bank details (submitted when making a donation).How do we use your personal information?We use your information to send you postal mailings, such as our supporter magazine, appeal updates and other information you have asked for or that we may feel would be of interest to you.We only use your email details to send you communications that you have requested.You can change the way we communicate with you, at any time, in the following ways:By calling our Freephone number 0808 178 4921By unsubscribing from specific emails, or managing your email preferences onlineBy emailing our Contact Centre at contactus@biblesociety.org.ukWhen you supply personal information to us, we only use this information for the purpose for which it was given and ensure that it is kept securely.We may carry out analysis of the personal information we collect about you and add publicly available information to create a profile of your interests, preferences and level of potential donations so we can contact you in the most appropriate way and with the most relevant information.From time to time we will ask our supporters to take part in surveys, to help us learn and improve how we work.Lawful basis for processing your informationWe use different reasons for using your information:Consent – sometimes we use your information to send you communications, such as emails, because you have given us clear consent to do soContract – we may process your personal data when we need to do this to fulfil a contract with you, e.g. if you have purchased something from our shopLegal Obligation – sometimes we will need to store your information because we have a legal reason to do this, e.g. if you have gift aided donations to us, HMRC require us to keep the information for up to 7 yearsLegitimate Interest – we will process your information when it is in our legitimate interest to do this and when these interests do not override your rights. Those legitimate interests include providing you with postal information e.g. fundraising appeals, BAM membership, supporter magazine etc.How long do we keep your information?We only keep your information for as long as we need to. We will have a lawful reason to keep your data and when we no longer need it, we will delete it. We will update this section soon, with examples of how long we will keep certain information.Do we share your personal information?We do not share your details with third parties, unless it is necessary to do so. Some of the ways it may be necessary to share your information include:fulfilling orderssending postal mail and emailanalysing dataproviding marketing assistanceprocessing financial transactions (see next section)other necessary functions.In cases like these, we will have a data agreement in place to ensure that these companies will not use your information for their own use, but only to fulfil the function on behalf of Bible Society.Your information will not be passed to third parties for marketing purposes.How do we use your financial information and keep it secure?In order to process financial transactions, we may need your bank or credit card details. We do not store credit card details nor do we share financial details with any 3rd parties.All credit card payments are processed by Sage Pay, via a secure server. Sage Pay privacy policy: https://www.sagepay.co.uk/policies/privacy-policyIf you have given us bank details in order to set up a direct debit, your information will be processed by Bible Society, within a secure hosting environment.Information you give us via the website is stored and processed in the UK. However, because of the nature of the internet, it is possible that your data may pass through countries outside the EEA.Your rights‘Right to be informed’ means we will be completely clear and transparent about how we plan to use your personal information.‘Right of access’ means you can request a copy of the personal information we hold about you and we will provide it within one month.‘Right to rectification’ means you can ask us to update or amend the information we hold about you, if it is incorrect.‘Right to restrict processing’ means you can ask us to change, restrict or stop the way we are using your information.‘Right to erasure’ (of right to be forgotten) means you can ask us to remove your personal information from our records.‘Right to object’ means you can object to us using your information for marketing purposes.‘Right to data portability’ means you can obtain and reuse your personal data for your own purposes.‘Right not to be subject to automated decision making’ means if we use systems to make a decision about you, you have the right to ask for a person to intervene, that then may change the outcome.Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, such as Fundraising Regulator or the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), if you are not satisfied with our response to your request, or you feel we are not using your information correctly.How we use CookiesFirst PartyOn some of our websites we use ‘Session Cookies’ which allow the website to link the actions of a user during a browser session. They are used for a variety of purposes such as remembering what a user has put in their shopping basket as they browse around a site (e.g. Bible Society Online Shop). These session cookies expire after a browser session is closed, so are never stored long term.Third PartyWe collect information about the Internet Protocol (IP) addresses of all our website visitors, using Google Analytics, in order to see how our website is used and monitor site traffic so as continuously improve and develop the design and content of our site. This information is not personally identifiable information – it is anonymised.From time to time we use Facebook to promote our websites and if you are a Facebook user you can click here to see how Facebook uses cookies for this purpose.Third Party – remarketingWe use third-party remarketing services, including the Facebook pixel, to help tailor advertising that we think may be of interest to users, based on their previous activity on our website. The adverts may appear on Facebook, or across the internet on third party sites, including those within Facebook’s Audience Network.Cookies are placed by third-party vendors, including Facebook, on web browsers to track user behaviour and serve ads related to such behaviour. No identifiable information is collected through the use of Facebook’s, or any other, third party remarketing service. Any data collected will be used in accordance with our privacy policy and Facebook’s privacy policy.You can opt out of Facebook’s use of cookies by visiting Facebook’s ad preference settings.Find out more about opting out of Internet-based advertising.To find out more information about cookies in general go to www.aboutcookies.orgSigning in using FacebookWhen setting up a Bible Society account (e.g. to purchase from our shop, or to register for Lyfe.etc.), you will be asked if you want to sign in using your Facebook account. This allows you to use your Facebook sign in and password, instead of creating a new profile for Bible Society. If you are not already signed into Facebook, you will be asked to sign in and it will tell you what information will be available to Bible Society.We will not see your password. We will only see your ‘Public profile’ information, but currently we are only using your first name and last name, and your Facebook email address if you allow it.ChildrenIf you are under 18, please get your parent/guardian’s consent before giving any personal information on our website.If you buy a book/bible from our online shop, you may get other shop emails from us. We will not knowingly send any other email or postal marketing material to those under 18.If you use social media platforms such as Facebook, Twitter and YouTube you may see Bible Society adverts. Please get your parent/guardian’s permission before giving personal information in response to these posts.How to contact usYou can get it touch with us in the following ways:through our online formby telephone 01793 418222by email at contactus@biblesociety.org.ukby post: Bible Society, Stonehill Green, Westlea, Swindon, SN5 7DG.How to update your detailsTo notify us of a change to your name, address or email details, please either complete our online form, email contactus@biblesociety.org.uk, write to us at the address below, or telephone us on 01793 418222. Please keep us informed of changes so we can stay in touch.If you have any concerns regarding this privacy policy or the way we are processing your personal information, please contact:The Data Protection Officer, at the address below, or email dataprotection@biblesociety.org.ukBible Society, Stonehill Green, Westlea, Swindon SN5 7DGLast revision: 03 December 2020
Didn’t find what you were looking for? Search the site Get in touch
Newsletter sign-up Get the latest on how we’re bringing the Bible to life around the world in a short, weekly email.
Sign up Email preferences
Our free apps Find out more Let’s get social
Facebook Twitter Instagram YouTube
Jobs See all vacancies Legal stuff © Copyright and permissions Privacy policy Cookie policy Terms and conditions Safeguarding summary Pension Scheme
Bringing the Bible to Life
British and Foreign Bible Society operates in England, Wales, the Channel Islands and the Isle of Man.And we also work with a network of local Bible Societies around the world. Find your closest Bible Society here Bible Society, Stonehill Green, Westlea, Swindon, SN5 7DG. Registered charity 232759
Search the site Get in touch
Sign up to newsletter Email preferences
Jobs Our apps © Copyright and permissions Privacy policy Cookie policy Terms and conditions Safeguarding summary Pension Scheme
Facebook Twitter Instagram YouTube
Bringing the Bible to life
Bible Society, Stonehill Green, Westlea, Swindon, SN5 7DG. Registered charity 232759
Processing, please wait
Read Bible
Open full Bible
